<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Git on Sherry's blog</title><link>https://www.xiaoli-yang.com/tags/git/</link><description>Recent content in Git on Sherry's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Content by Xiaoli Yang</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 15:06:14 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.xiaoli-yang.com/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Three-Stage Branch Model applied in DevOps - CI part</title><link>https://www.xiaoli-yang.com/2020/07/29/three-stage-branch-model-applied-in-devops-ci-part/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 15:06:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.xiaoli-yang.com/2020/07/29/three-stage-branch-model-applied-in-devops-ci-part/</guid><description>I am working on a data platform project, the product itself is composed of several microservices. Our team is under great pressure of operation and mantainance. Thanks to the DevOps helps us keep the balance of development and deployment.
In this post, I illustrate how we maintain the CI(continuous integration) part, which contains: the branch strategy we adopt, the concept of DevOps, overview of the workflow, the tips.
next post, I will continue to explain the CD part(cotinous deployment)</description></item><item><title>Advanced Git Usage</title><link>https://www.xiaoli-yang.com/2019/06/28/advanced-git-usage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 09:57:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.xiaoli-yang.com/2019/06/28/advanced-git-usage/</guid><description>Introduction Git works more than as a version controlling tool, it glues the teamwork together. It is widely used by almost all developers nowadays. Basic usages can be git-cheatsheet
However, in some scenarios, more advanced skills are required. In this post, I will present some usages, which can impove our efficiency.
1. git stash: store temporary dirty working branch Scenario: Interrupted workflow When you are in the middle of coding, your boss comes in and demands that you fix something immediately.</description></item></channel></rss>